SHIVAM SOM

+917011854210 | shivam.som0101@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Leetcode | GitHub | Hacker Rank

Professional Summary

Technology driven software engineer with over 3 years' experience in development, configuration & optimization of integrated business & Enterprise application solutions. Proficient in configuring and optimizing operating systems and development environments across frontend and backend programming languages and deployment Architecture.

Professional Skills

Languages & Frameworks: C/C++, Python, Django, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Next.js, Vue.js, MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js), Redux, Jest & Enzyme, GraphQL.

Data Structures & Databases: DSA, OOPs, DBMS, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Compass DB, Redis

DevOps & Cloud Technologies: AWS, Azure DevOps, CI/CD, Networking, Docker, SDLC, Git, Jira, Firebase, Shopify

Work Experience

ARCELORMITTAL GROUP – Software Development Engineer (Remote)

March 2023 - Present

Chrome Extension Plugin:

- Independently created a security-focused Chrome extension that detected and blocked 95% of malicious web requests, resulting in a 30% increase in user safety feedback ratings within the first quarter.
- Applied algorithms that cut URL matching time by 50%, boosting user engagement metrics.

Tech Stack Used: MERN stack, Redis, JS/TS, MongoDB, Agile SDLC methodologies, Requirement Elicitation, BRD

RBAC Admin Template:

- Implemented RBAC Admin Template that sped up SAAS development by 40%.
- Optimized legacy code of the Admin Template, cutting unauthorized data access by 40%, bolstering security.

Tech Stack Used: Python, SQL databases, React.js, Azure DevOps, MUI, ANTD, CI/CD, Django Rest Framework

Collections Tool I2C Process:

- Built an API-integrated tool that improved cash flow velocity by 25% and reduced processing times by 15%.
- Engineered an innovative tool with seamless API integration, improving cash flow velocity by 30%.

Tech Stack Used: Python (ML), DevOps, Next JS, Redis, Jest & Enzyme, Leading Development Initiatives

BENTHON LABS – Software Engineer (NOIDA)

January 2022 - March 2023

- Developed a robust MERN Stack web app for SOLDOUT, by utilizing AWS and Shopify integration, showcasing proficiency in MongoDB, Node.js, and AWS services, increasing sales by 20% and improves system performance.
- > Spearheaded the design and development of CREDELLO's responsive mobile and desktop applications, demonstrating a 30% improvement, leveraging React JS, Cognito, TypeScript, and MERN stack technologies.
- > Leveraged a diverse tech stack to optimize workflows, achieving a 50% reduction in development time and significantly enhancing deployment efficiency across multiple projects.
- Elevated IQUANTI's UI capabilities through Redux and Saga integration, resulting in a 35% increase in application responsiveness and a 20% boost in user satisfaction metrics.

Tech Stack Used: MERN Stack, Redux, Saga, TS, AWS, Vue JS, Shopify, Jira, Jenkins, SQL & NoSQL DB, Git, SDLC.

Education		Internships			
>	B.Tech in CSE	July 2018 - June 2022	>	MERN STACK INTERN	September 2021 - December 2021
	(IMS ENGINEERING COLLEGE)			(SSJ IT SOLUTIONS)	
>	DIPLOMA in Programming	July 2017 - June 2018	>	SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTER	N May 2021 - August 2021
	(DICS INSTITUTE)			(JP MORGAN)	
>	12 th : Science	July 2015 - June 2017	>	WEB DEVELOPER INTERN	January 2021 - April 2021
	(INGRAHAM INSTITUTE)			(SAARTHI ORGANIZATION)	